Lluís Pellejà

Data analyst & Data Scientist



□ lluispeso@gmail.com

L +34 620 301 543

lluispelleja.com

in Lluís Pellejà

I am a highly qualified professional who's main goal is to start a new career in Switzerland as a Dat analyst or Data Scientist, the past three years I worked meanwhile I was studying my bachelor degree and my masters degree. I consider myself as a proactive person, who doesn't fear new challenges and is capable of work under pressure. I think that with my combined studies and working experience, I can contribute a lot to any company that give me the opportunity to develop my skills to another level.

Experience

Market Research Analyst -----

----- Sep 2022 - Dec 2023

In this job opportunity I have learned many skills such as team management, problem-solving and communication skills, in turn I have improved my skills as a data analyst using daily tools such as Python and APIs to solve problems and increase the efficiency of the department. In this job I have carried out the following functions:

- Create an entire app programed with Python that reduces the time consuming tasks at only one click, automatizing all the process with scrips and a machine Learning model which detects which companies have more importance for the Department of Sales.
- Create databases of target companies so that the SDR team could call the companies and generate sales
- Analyse all data from the Sales and SDR team, to make decisions at a fast pace, justified with data. These decisions were made with the aim of achieving more sales and opportunities.

Marketing & Sales Analyst ----- Jun 2021 - Aug 2022

Once I finished my internship in the marketing department of Movertis, I was given the opportunity to continue in the company as Marketing & Sales Analyst, this job opportunity has taught me the world of data analysis, which I completely fell in love with and motivated me to continue my training in this subject.

- Data analysis for commercial prospecting in order to generate more sales in a more optimal way.
- Analysis of databases using technologies such as Python R and SQL in order to draw conclusions from different marketing campaigns.
- Creation of automations in Excel using Python, these automations were to generate more value by automating the most repetitive tasks and spending more time on the parts of the department that brought the most value to the business.
- Management of Pipedrive (CRM), in this task I performed dashboard maintenance and data collection, as well as data monitoring to manage the whole SDR team.
- Project management with the market research team to generate new strategies and update sales tactics to optimise efforts.

Trainee Program (Marketing Analyst) ----- Mar 2021 - May 2021

I came to Movertis to do my internship for my International Business degree, I joined the internship in the marketing department where I developed a lot of interesting skills and gained a lot of new knowledge.

- Market research and analysis, data collection to see the state of the company against its competitors and the market.
- Data management in CRM

Lluís Pellejà Data analyst & Data Scientist

Education

Kschool - Master in Data Science

-- November 2022 - October 2023

In this master we work on everything related to Data Science, from data collection, modeling and visualization. In order to achieve the objectives and carry out the work that we are going to find as analysts, we are learning the following technologies:

- Programming in Python
- Python packages such as Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Sklearn, Streamlit, etc.
- Frameworks such as Kedro to develop projects stable and scalable
- Programming in R
- Data visualization in both Python and R
- Development of supervised and unsupervised learning models in both Python and R

We are also doing a TFM that consists of creating your own Data Science project, in my case I am automating an entire department to make it more efficient using the data and technologies that we have at our disposal.

ESERP Business & Law School - International Business ----- September 2018 - June 2022

In the degree I have developed the necessary knowledge to do a complete business planning, in almost all the departments of a company, from marketing to business strategy. The degree was largely focused not only on business strategy, but also on the management of international companies and how we can adapt them in any environment depending on the culture and conditions of each country.

In the degree, develop the following skills:

- Business planning
- Business analysis
- Planning of real internationalization
- Adaptation of companies in different contexts of the world
- Analysis of different markets in the world (mainly Asia)
- Project management in different sectors

Skills

Technical skills

- Python
- Scrapping web
- R
- Tableau
- SQL
- Docker
- Excel
- Streamlit
- GIT
- Scikit-learn
- Kedro
- RestFul-APIs
- AWS
- Pandas

Soft skills

- Active listeningCritical thinking
- Verval & written com.
- Motivation
- Strategic mind
- · Stress management
- · Logical reasoning

Languages

Spanish (native) Catalan (native) English (fluent B2)







Projects

PROJECT 1 - Automatization of leads generation

At this project the main goal was to create a system which can generate target companies for the Sales department in an automatic way. The pinacle of this project is that in order to extract more information it uses a machine learning model and this feature ensures the data quality of the companies.

PROJECT 2 - Creation of a KPI Dashboard

In this project, the main goal was to create a stable and scalable dashboard which it contains all the KPIs of the SDR team, these KPIs were from multiple platforms so the main goal was to unify the data in order to see the whole picture in one only site. Nowadays, the dashboard is self-sufficient and provides data in real time to take decisions quickly.